<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GirlPilates - Free Pilates for Every Woman</title><link>https://girlpilates.com/</link><description>Recent content on GirlPilates - Free Pilates for Every Woman</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://girlpilates.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Hundred</title><link>https://girlpilates.com/exercises/mat/the-hundred/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://girlpilates.com/exercises/mat/the-hundred/</guid><description>The Hundred is Joseph Pilates&amp;rsquo; signature exercise and the traditional opening of every classical Pilates mat routine. It&amp;rsquo;s designed to warm up your body, engage your powerhouse (core), and coordinate your breath with movement.
Why It&amp;rsquo;s Called &amp;ldquo;The Hundred&amp;rdquo; You pump your arms 100 times total while holding your core engaged. This creates internal heat and prepares your body for the exercises that follow.
Benefits Core Endurance: Holding the position builds stamina in your deep abdominal muscles Breath Coordination: The rhythmic breathing pattern oxygenates your blood Full Body Warm-Up: Engages arms, core, and legs simultaneously Mind-Body Connection: Requires focus and concentration Common Mistakes to Avoid Tensing the neck - Keep your gaze at your belly button, not the ceiling Holding your breath - Maintain the 5-count inhale, 5-count exhale pattern Arching the lower back - Press your lower back gently into the mat Pumping from shoulders - Initiate the arm movement from your lats Tips for Success Start with the beginner modification and progress over time Quality over quantity - better to do 50 pumps with proper form than 100 with poor form Focus on the exhale to deepen your core engagement</description></item><item><title>The Roll Up</title><link>https://girlpilates.com/exercises/mat/roll-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://girlpilates.com/exercises/mat/roll-up/</guid><description>The Roll Up is one of the most challenging mat exercises and a true test of core strength. It requires controlled articulation of the spine - moving one vertebra at a time - which builds both strength and flexibility.
Benefits Core Strength: Targets deep abdominal muscles Spinal Mobility: Improves vertebrae-by-vertebrae movement Flexibility: Stretches the entire back body Control: Develops mind-muscle connection Tips for Success Imagine peeling your spine off the mat like a wheel Keep your feet grounded throughout the movement Move slowly - momentum is cheating!</description></item><item><title>Workout Generator</title><link>https://girlpilates.com/workouts/generator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://girlpilates.com/workouts/generator/</guid><description>Build Your Perfect Workout Select your preferences below and we&amp;rsquo;ll generate a balanced Pilates routine just for you.</description></item></channel></rss>